[Music]
hi everybody welcome back to the channel
i'm nick and today on polar ice creamery
we are gonna deal with
caramel cone explosion
[Music]
[Laughter]
that's been asked for a few times
strangely enough
and
it was definitely for sale in canada
when we were there we saw it it's the
one of the haagen-dazs extras with a
nice dark colored tubs and tubs look
really good um
but it was a little bit of research
showed that shows that caramel cone was
a previous flavor that is no longer
available but it was different to the
caramel cone explosion that you get now
from what i can tell the original flavor
had
swirls of caramel through it
and
chocolate covered cone pieces and the
new one has
the
almond
they call it praline but we over here
would call it brittle
so
along with the chocolate covered cone
pieces and a caramel ice cream oh my god
there's so many things that they change
let's just see what we end up with
so the first thing for this caramel cone
explosion monstrosity is the caramel so
we're going to start with the sugar add
into that little bit of water that's two
tablespoons of water in there and then
get it boiling away no stirring just
swirling
once it starts to turn a light brown
color keep an eye on it because it will
start to turn dark very quickly at that
point
once it's turned the color that you want
turn the heat off and gently add in your
cream and your butter
remember this will bubble up quite a lot
so just be prepared for that
it doesn't bubble up as much if your
butter is warm but i find that the
caramel separates much easier with warm
butter so
keep stirring and eventually it will all
come together at which point you can
take your caramel off the heat and put
it to the side
so the next stage is the actual ice
cream itself what we're gonna do is
surprise surprise we're gonna start with
our milk and bring in our other
ingredients here we've got our sugar
which got stabilizer in it
and then we're going to add in our
dextrose and once that comes up to a
nominal temperature that could be
anything from 30 to 50 degrees we're
going to add in our skim milk powder get
that nicely combined and then at that
stage we're going to bring in our
caramel that we made we're going to put
the whole lot
into this ice cream base stir it well
and just keep it warmed somewhere at 50
to 60 degree mark you need to make sure
that caramel is completely incorporated
into the base
once it's ready you can take it off the
heat and put it in a container and then
add in your cream
give it a final stir and then put it in
the fridge
[Music]
the next i'm going to do is deal with
the almonds so this is where we're going
to make our praline
slash brittle whatever you want to call
it wherever you are there seems to be a
bit of an
unusual situation with praline and
brittle they're called different things
in different places but either way
what's in the ice cream is relatively
hard chunks of caramel
with
almond pieces in it and that's what
we're going to make here we're going to
take our blanched almonds and put them
on a baking tray and pop them in the
oven at 175 for about 15 to 20 minutes
just to get them toasted slightly and
bring the flavor forward a bit more
then once they finished we're going to
start with the caramel part of this
almond praline slash brittle again we're
gonna we're gonna add our sugar and
water into the pan and get it nice and
hot bubbling away until we get to the
color that we want
at that stage we're gonna take the
almonds out of the oven the oven is off
at this stage
and we're going to
blitz them in our blender no we don't
want to get them powdered but we just
want to make them a bit smaller you
could smash them with a rolling pin if
you want whatever works for you just
break them up into smaller pieces
then you can see we've got a nice golden
color to the caramel we are going to add
in our almond pieces into that give it a
nice good stir this is a great stage
actually if you didn't get the depth of
color you wanted just keep it on the
heat just keep it on heat stirring it
well
and eventually that camera will come to
the color that you want a little bit
more controllably
once it's reached that color take it off
the heat and put it on a silicone baking
tray get it flat and let it cool down
completely
the final element of this ice cream is
the chocolate covered
waffle cone pieces
so
apparently it's a milk chocolate so
we're going to take our milk chocolate
we're going to melt it in the microwave
and just going to add in a teaspoon or
two of neutral tasting coconut oil you
don't want this to taste a coconut at
all so go for one of the deodorized
coconut oils
once that's completely mixed in we're
going to take our cone pieces and we're
going to dip them in the chocolate now
i'm going to try this two ways because
the first way look just looks really
messy
and i mean literally got chocolate
everywhere as you can see it's all over
my fingers it's on the floor it's on the
walls it's on the child it chocolate
literally everywhere if you've seen me
work with chocolate you know i am
rubbish at it
so
we're gonna keep going with those and
then we're gonna try the final plan of
taking all the remaining cone pieces put
them in the chocolate tub and mix it all
together and put it in one big lump on
that little pan there and we're gonna
shove that whole thing in the fridge and
just see what happens
now we're ready to break up our almond
praline or brittle
and we're just gonna put it on a nice
surface and smash it up just like that
and magic they're all in little cubes
into the pots
so before we actually prepare the ice
cream in your machine we're going to get
all our components ready that means take
it out your chocolate covered waffle
pieces put them in a container keep them
in the freezer until the last minute and
we're actually now gonna look at
churning some ice cream thankfully so
with your ice cream base completely
chilled in the fridge take it out give
it a final mix so the final few minutes
of churning your ice cream you're going
to add in your almond praline bits
if you've not got a strong ice cream
machine i recommend you add these after
you've put it in your tub but we've got
a nice strong machine so we can add it
all in and it'll crunch it up nicely
once that's mixed in the last little bit
is to add in your chocolate covered
waffle pieces
just get that mixed in for a few seconds
turn your machine off and load the tub
up put it in freezer for a few hours
until you're ready to eat it
there is a lot to this ice cream my wife
has just passed the tub to me at the
freezer let's get some scooped up and
see what we ended up with shall we
look at that tub
it's amazing
big explosion lots of caramel lots of
waffle covered pieces
scoopy scoopy
let's chat more scoop
[Music]
scooped really well i mean it's been out
of the freezer for a couple of minutes
so i probably recommend you do the same
thing
the
little almondy pieces
[Applause]
are really nice
really helps with that toast the
toastiness comes through
i wasn't sure whether it would or not
almonds don't toast amazingly well
but that's really nice it's got a kind
of woody
note to the caramel so you get that
it's almost peanut kind of flavor coming
through but
ultimately it's really really good
let's see what this tastes like shall we
[Music]
corny
get off my beard
a couple of surprising things that
neither of us thought would happen one
is
this does not go rock solid in the ice
cream
which is really pleasantly surprising
because unless you've got good teeth
some chunks of caramel and ice cream are
like bullets
that's not done it
it just it just falls apart in your
mouth very much like it does not in the
ice cream so that's really good and
second
is the chocolate covered cone pieces
completely crunchy still so making sure
that they're completely covered in
chocolate helps obviously keep the cone
away from the ice cream stops from going
soggy
etc etc
um the waffle cones were just
store-bought we don't have the means to
make them at home and i'm certainly not
going to buy a machine just to make
those for this video
but you can buy waffle cones basically
anywhere in your supermarket in your
local ice cream shop i'm sure they'll
sell some too if you want them
but a few people have asked for this and
it turned out a really good ice cream
really nice strong caramel flavor to the
ice cream base
nice texture change between the waffle
pieces and the caramel pieces and the
ice cream overall i'm really impressed
with this flavor if this is something
that you can get
then you know let us know what you think
let us know if the recipe change
really did your nuttin
if you're english
um
but we could only find it in canada so
we don't know if it is available
anywhere else but let us know in the
comments if you can get this where you
are and if you are going to make this
one i mean there is a fair few bits to
this ice cream not going to lie but
you know good things come to those who
wait
anyway
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
[Music]